[music]
If that lemon sorbet looks perfect to
you, and it should, it's because it is.
And that's what we're doing today, both
in a Ninja Creamy and in a CH machine.
So, let's get on and make it. What are
we going to need for this perfect lemon
sorbet? You are going to need 44 gram of
arythril,
gram of sugar, 75 g of lemon juice,
[music] 20 g of lemon zest, 1,100
g of water, 71 g of glucose,
5.5 g of zantham gum, and 2 g of citric
acid. The balance of ingredients for
sorbet are really important, but not as
important as the method of making it.
We're using arythrtol to balance our
freezing point so we don't add too many
solids. We're using citric acid to boost
the acidity, which is super important in
sorbets to create that pop of flavor
that we need. We're using glucose syrup,
but you absolutely can use light corn
syrup in this. It's basically the same
thing. Glucose syrup is available in
most European supermarkets in North
America. just go for light corn syrup.
We're using Zantham gum because we don't
want to overheat this. We want to keep
this down low. So, the first thing we
need to do is deal with our lemons.
We're simply going to take our
microplane and get as much of that lemon
zest off as possible, avoiding that
white pith underneath. It's really
bitter and we don't want that in our
sorbet.
20 g of lemon zest equates to the zest
of two large lemons.
You don't have to be super accurate with
that measurement. As long as you're
taking the zest from two large lemons,
that's fine. So, there is our zest. Now,
we're going to weigh out our lemon
juice. Going to cut these in half. I
have rolled these really well on the
counter, softened the flesh up, and that
just breaks apart the fibers within the
lemon so that it releases that juice so
that now when we cut it and squeeze it,
we get more liquid out. So, let's do
that and get our 75 g of lemon juice
prepared.
So, now the two large lemons gave us
about 80 g of lemon juice. So, that's
perfect. This is a 1,750
g batch. 750 g we're going to use for
our Ninja Creamy Deluxe. And the rest
we're going to use for our churn
machine. What we're going to do is we're
going to take some of our sugar and just
put it in a small container like that.
And we're going to pop our lemon zest
into there and just combine that gently.
So, what we're actually doing here is
partially creating an oolio saccharum
which is Latin for oil sugar. And it's
essentially a concentrated syrup made by
extracting the oils from citrus peel.
But we're not going to let it go that
far for this ice cream. We're going to
leave that for about 30 minutes to do
its thing. You can skip this phase if
you want to. I just like to show people
how to do things slightly different ways
sometimes. But if you don't want to do
this, absolutely don't need to. Now,
let's get our water in our pan, which is
1,100 g or milliliters. It's the same
thing.
And into that we are going to put in our
arythrtol which is mixed with our citric
acid and our zantham gum. We're just
going to tiny whisk those together.
And we're doing that just to break up
any zantham gum lumps and make sure
everything's fully incorporated. Now we
can combine that with our water. I'm
going to get a whisk and stir that
together. We're going to heat this up
but not too high cuz we're using zantham
which is a cold process stabilizer.
Anyway, next we're going to put in the
rest of our sugar.
Now, we're going to pop this on heat and
bring this up to a syrup phase. So,
about 50 Celsius, which is this in
Fahrenheit. And what that will do is
completely dissolve our sugars, allow
that zanthan gum to actually start doing
its job. Then we can start adding the
final parts of our recipe together. So,
let's get that on heat now. So, what is
an oolio saccharum? That is essentially
just oil and sugar. It's a syrup usually
used for lemons but can be used for any
fruit that has the oil in the skin. So
citrus fruit mainly generally it's made
by osmosis. So the oils being pulled out
naturally without any inclusion of heat
or anything. And that's just a case of
uh doing what we did earlier. Combine
them and leave it to sit for a at least
half an hour. You can do this overnight.
You can do this a week ahead if you
want. And you'll be left with a sugar
syrup as the oils combine with that
sugar, dissolve the sugar solids, and
create a syrup. We probably won't get to
the syrup phase here because we're not
leaving it for enough time. But as we're
heating this up, you absolutely don't
need to do this. You can just put the
lemon zest in with the base here and
heat it up. And then let it sit once
it's up to temperature for about half an
hour. It will do the same kind of thing.
Two different ways of getting to the
same result. Right, we're up to our
syrup phase. So, we've created this semi
viscous, semi-transparent liquid. That's
a really important step for sorbets. We
need to create that semi viscous base.
It's simply the best way to create it.
Something with ice cream science is it's
more about how you get there rather than
what you use to get there. So, the
method is often much more important than
ingredients you use. As long as you
balance the sugar content for
crystallization, recristallization,
ice crystal formation, and freezing
point and serving temperature, the rest
is kind of, you know, not irrelevant,
but less relevant. So, now that we've
got our syrup phase done, we can add in
our glucose syrup.
We'll stir that in. The heat is enough
to dissolve that straight in.
Ing goes our lemon juice.
It's important to note you cannot use
guir for this recipe. Guard does not
work in acidic bases. It simply will not
do its job. Zantham will work in acidic
bases. So that's something if you use
stabilizers that's super important to
remember. If you're using a combination
stabilizer that uses locust bean gum,
gua, you know, carrageenan, something
like that, it's less important because
the other two will do the job
ultimately, but guar won't be effective
in this recipe. Finally, we can add in
our oolio sacarum. I mean, it's barely
an oolio saccharum to be fair because uh
you really should leave this for about
24 hours. You can leave it in the
fridge. That's absolutely fine. I had
this conversation with someone in the in
the comments a few weeks ago why I don't
do this. It's just not important in this
phase because we're heating our bases
up. We're removing the oils from the
zest during that phase anyway. So, it's
it's not an important phase, but it's a
good lesson to learn cuz you can use
this for all baking recipes as well.
It's a it's a really good way to extract
oils from the zest of citrus fruit so
that you can use them in basically
anything. So, now that's all combined,
we can simply stir that together. You'll
find it becomes really, really quite
thick, just like an ice cream base
would. Now, you got two options here.
Strain this to remove all of that lemon
zest out of there if you want.
Personally, I like to see this in my
sorbes. It creates a nice kind of visual
effect for me. It's totally up to you.
Won't have any effect on the recipe
apart from by leaving it in, we allow
more time for more of that oil to be
extracted. So, with that said and done,
get our containers. So, we got our Ninja
Creamy Tub here.
Beautiful. In that goes. The viscosity
should just be enough so that the lemon
zest stays within the body and doesn't
sink to the bottom. Um, but if you
really want it distributed, again, with
Ninja Creamy, the blades are going to go
down and come back up. It's going to
distribute itself naturally. But
otherwise, just give it a quick shake or
a stir partway through freezing. So,
let's pop that in the freezer and let's
put the rest into another container.
And as we haven't superheated this, this
can go straight in the refrigerator
without any problems. Again, we're going
to probably leave this overnight to let
those flavors build. And we will come
back tomorrow when we compare the two
versions of this amazing, possibly the
best lemon sorbet you're ever going to
eat. Lemon goes well with lots of
things, but my personal favorite is that
torched meringue. So, I've got some high
protein
Swiss meringue in the refrigerator from
another bake. So, I'm going to torch
that on the top, but I'll show you how I
torch that later on. But for now, let's
leave those to settle down and I'll see
you tomorrow. If you want to win one of
these heated ice cream scoops, then make
sure to watch this video in its
entirety. How many times have I said the
word torch? So, make sure you count
those up. Make sure you like this video,
you're subscribed to the channel, and in
the comments, put how many times I say
that word torch. It's probably not as
obvious as you might think. In 7 days, I
will take all the correct answers, put
them into the a randomizer, and pull out
a winner. This competition is worldwide,
so don't forget to enter to win a super
cool heated ice cream scoop.
So, with that said and done, I've
pre-chilled the cher machine down for
about 5 minutes as I normally do and got
some of that mix in there spinning away.
And we're going to do our Ninja Creamy
Deluxe on the sorbet setting. Obviously,
the sorbet setting is considerably
faster spin rate than the normal ice
cream and chelatte setting. And if you
weren't aware, the ice cream and gelata
settings are identical in every single
way. So, don't really worry too much.
Now, with both of those prepped, I mean,
the spin one is nearly there. We're
going to pop them back into the freezer
to fully harden off so that it's a level
playing field. I don't want one to be
naturally softer than the other one
because I want to get that heated ice
cream scoop out [music] and see how that
does as well. Now loading up this. I
mean, I can instantly [music] tell the
texture of this one is perfect. And, you
know, I'm really looking forward to
[music] trying this.
Our two sorbets, lemon sorbes. Perfect.
scooping the small one here is our Ninja
Creamy. Let's dig into that one. Texture
is amazing.
It's so so good. I'm always disappointed
when I buy sorbets from stores, scoop
shops, whatever, because it just doesn't
cut the mustard. The the texture is like
really icy with not a lot of flavor. And
those are the two main things you need
for a sorbet. You need that texture to
be absolutely spot on. You need that
flavor to be spot on. Without both of
those, perfect. A sorbet will always let
you down. And Ninja Creamies do sorbet
better than anything else. Let's try the
churned one.
Ever slightly lighter. It has the
strange effect of being less cold, and
that's because there's a little bit of
air incorporated in during the churning
phase, which is how it's meant to be.
But, you know, to be fair, the Ninja
Creamy does an excellent job with
sorbets. It just creates a ever so
slight difference in texture.
I love seeing those flexcks of lemon
zest in there as well. And to me, it
creates a better aesthetic to see
exactly what it is. It's creating that
flavor. There's no artificial flavorings
in here. Pure, unadulterated
lemon sorbet. Perfect lemon sorbet.
Let's get some higher protein meringue
on top. Let's torch this. What do we
have there? Lemon meringue sorbet.
that's good. Honestly, I think
I've taken that lemon sorbet, which is
the best lemon sorbet I have ever eaten
and just elevated it right up to 11. If
you know the reference, comment below.
Perfect. Perfect lemon sorbet in the
Ninja Creamy and a Churn machine. ever
so slight different result. Nobody
really is going to be able to tell apart
from those that are deeply into their
ice cream and making. Give this one a
try. Super easy to do. The stabilizer
isn't optional in this. That Zantham gum
or whatever stabilizer it is you use
really is the key to creating the best
saw you're ever going to have. So, you
can buy zantham gum super cheap on
Amazon pretty much across the world. You
don't need a huge amount. You could buy
a 100 gram pouch and it would last you
probably an entire year of ice cream
making. Don't forget to enter the
giveaway for the heated ice cream scoop.
This did an excellent job. I just want
to try one more thing. Dense dense
chocolate ice cream. This has been in
the freezer for about five weeks. So,
it's hard and it's it's a high solid
chocolate ice cream as well. So, it's
really hard. this little scoop. Charge
it up USBC and you just hold both sides.
There's two little pressure pads on each
side and that heats the scoop up. You
can feel it heating up as well. So,
let's see how it deals with this. Look
at that.
Not exaggerating. That little scoop has
done a perfect perfect [music] job even
on high solids ultra hard ice cream
straight out the freezer that hasn't
been adjusted at all. That is how that
scoop [music] works. If you want to
enter then make sure to like this video.
Make sure you subscribe to the channel
and comment below how many times I
[music] have said torch. In a week's
time, I will gather all the correct
entries, put them into a randomizer, and
pick out the winner. This competition is
open worldwide, so make sure to enter.
Thanks very much for watching. Don't
forget to like and subscribe. See you
next week. [music]
>> [music]